[{"id": "5fd81fdfd0de9af39e9d469a", "question": "What year did Amazon.com make its first sale?", "answer": "1995", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7da", "question": "What is the world's largest lake crossed by the equator?", "answer": "Lake Victoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a9e92f47ccba3ffe45786bf", "question": "Who is the main protagonist of the 1932 novel \"Cold Comfort Farm\"?", "answer": "Flora Poste", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e1", "question": "What TV show takes place in Pawnee, Indiana?", "answer": "Parks and Recreation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39a", "question": "What year was the American Red Cross founded?", "answer": "1881", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d19", "question": "What popular musician's last name is Sarkisian LaPiere?", "answer": "Cher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c67d", "question": "A group of rhinos is called a what?", "answer": "A crash", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe73405eec85e375820b22b", "question": "How old was the youngest American serviceman in World War II?", "answer": "12", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be74", "question": "Who were the winners of the James E. Sullivan Award for amateur athletics in 1986 and 1988?", "answer": "Jackie Joyner-Kersee and Florence Griffith-Joyner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ab1b2aa4fda37788a9a1dbc", "question": "Scotophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Darkness", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e67bfe83fe1f2a824bcd", "question": "What, in the 16th and 17th centuries, was a \"drunkard\u2019s cloak\"?", "answer": "It was a form of humiliation used to address people who were perceived as abusers of alcohol.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ad", "question": "What nationality was Pablo Picasso?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002447a4be4723ccac221a4", "question": "How long did it take Leonardo da Vinci to paint the Mona Lisa's smile?", "answer": "Leonardo's greatest triumph was the smile of the Mona Lisa, which he labored on for 16 years up until his death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fffa6a173838c5c8a417f30", "question": "How many teeth does an aardvark have?", "answer": "None", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a544", "question": "Which US state is home to Clemson University?", "answer": "South Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f32d01dd7bf43be5e815", "question": "What does SPF stand for?", "answer": "Sun Protection Factor", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339300", "question": "What song does Ferris Bueller sing from the float in the Chicago parade?", "answer": "Twist and Shout", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f457caf848b908361b873", "question": "Who became president of Brazil in 2019?", "answer": "Jair Bolsonaro", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b852", "question": "What two baseball players make up the battery?", "answer": "The pitcher and the catcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e6e", "question": "Who played the blind character in the movie \"Red Dragon\"?", "answer": "Emily Watson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb7", "question": "What dish is prepared by frying a breaded, buttered chicken breast?", "answer": "Chicken Kiev", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049be6cf93664eb10486a2", "question": "The \"Eisner Award\" is named after which influential cartoonist and writer?", "answer": "Will Eisner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac4a", "question": "How did Socrates commit suicide?", "answer": "By drinking poison hemlock", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76f3eeec85e375820b2e5", "question": "What is the most mountainous country in Europe?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b55", "question": "Which ear did artist Vincent Van Gogh cut off?", "answer": "Left", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76c", "question": "What explorer introduced chickens to the New World?", "answer": "Christopher Columbus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2af", "question": "What nation was led by Casimir the Great?", "answer": "Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ed", "question": "What member of Fleetwood Mac released a 1981 solo hit single titled \"Trouble\"?", "answer": "Lindsey Buckingham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133984a", "question": "Who played Chad Gates in the 1961 movie \"Blue Hawaii\"?", "answer": "Elvis Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffb5b835dad637d903c881b", "question": "What is the most-popular meat served on Christmas in the United Kingdom?", "answer": "Turkey meat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be89", "question": "What type of a tree killed Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Oak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c790", "question": "What color is the octopus blood?", "answer": "Light blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b89", "question": "What is the number of thieves that Alibaba had?", "answer": "40", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22f", "question": "Which cartoon character has a girlfriend named Petunia?", "answer": "Porky Pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4b6", "question": "What process includes the following phases: prophase, metaphase, anaphase, and telophase?", "answer": "Cell mitosis", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398d9", "question": "What movie starred Sean Penn playing the role of gay rights activist Harvey Milk?", "answer": "Milk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b83b", "question": "How many horizontal rows of stars are there on the U.S. flag?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393b8", "question": "Which character did Tom Hanks play in the movie \"The Da Vinci Code\"?", "answer": "Robert Langdon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b660", "question": "What US auto maker produced a car called the Cirrus?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff670f552a821ff76ae8b23", "question": "Who invented \"Jell-O\"?", "answer": "Pearle Wait", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399db", "question": "What 2005 Gwen Stefani song was the first single to amass one million paid digital downloads?", "answer": "Hollaback Girl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3df", "question": "What was the first vitamin to be discovered and named?", "answer": "Vitamin A", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b4e1e662d71a53650ff1", "question": "Which of Edgar Allen Poe's works was written in honor of his wife?", "answer": "Annabel Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f6", "question": "What garden vegetable was known for years as green Italian squash?", "answer": "Zucchini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbc942760f0007efaba0e5d", "question": "What does the abbreviation BC stand for?", "answer": "Before Christ", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067a28ff9c0647b50a8054", "question": "Which Japanese company manufactured the final videocassette recorder on July 22, 2016?", "answer": "Funai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d32", "question": "What future US congressman co-wrote the Searchers' 1964 hit \"Needles and Pins\"?", "answer": "Sonny Bono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc0f8ec223966ae8f8862", "question": "Why were the Boston Red Sox said to be \"cursed\" between 1918 and 2004?", "answer": "For trading Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a8", "question": "How many years did prohibition last in the US?", "answer": "13", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a97b", "question": "What nation's legislative body is named The Kuvendi?", "answer": "Albania", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a371", "question": "Where is the Darjeeling tea grown?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59068111ff9c0647b50a8091", "question": "Before disbanding in 2016, who was the vocalist for the band \"Gossip\"?", "answer": "Beth Ditto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fd", "question": "What takes place every July in Pamplona?", "answer": "The running of the bulls", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd95", "question": "What was the pseudonym of famous cross-dresser Amandine-Aurore-Lucile Dupin?", "answer": "George Sand", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ca", "question": "What is the minimum number of bars on an abacus?", "answer": "Nine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e5", "question": "What year was actor W. C. Fields born?", "answer": "1880", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b711", "question": "What contribution to Christmas is John Calcott Horsely credited with?", "answer": "The first mass-produced Christmas card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9e", "question": "What singer's manager for over two decades was Colonel Tom Parker?", "answer": "Elvis Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d7", "question": "Who traditionally occupied the Peacock Throne?", "answer": "The shah of Iran", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58f16b40f7c52aae91cc07e5", "question": "What is the name of the apartment complex the Jetsons live in?", "answer": "Skypad Apartments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9b770364247bf200fb872", "question": "Which 1993 Disney movie starred Bette Midler as a witch?", "answer": "Hocus Pocus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9431574a5ce6b56b8244", "question": "What job did Agatha Christie's second husband do?", "answer": "Archaeologist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7bdef877e98cb9777895b", "question": "What mountain is nicknamed the \"Savage Mountain\"?", "answer": "K-2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b8d78a2b42d4a3561a9f0e", "question": "Which Russian novelist wrote the short story \u201cThe Queen of Spades\u201d?", "answer": "Alexander Pushkin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59774549284458f1d7854435", "question": "What language was the 1966 film \"Incubus\" made in?", "answer": "Esperanto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a425", "question": "What is Peru's capital?", "answer": "Lima", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febafbe7e83c707845b20ff", "question": "What causes the phenomenon of red \"watermelon snow\"?", "answer": "Algae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66cfea5bfecdd737e0899", "question": "Where is the original London Bridge structure today?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389be", "question": "What country provides the setting for \"The King and I\"?", "answer": "Siam (Thailand)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133893d", "question": "What was the name of Vincent van Gogh's art dealer brother?", "answer": "Theo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a889", "question": "What two US state capitals are named for people who were executed?", "answer": "Raleigh and St. Paul", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015f858fe83fe1f2a824c2c", "question": "Under whose presidency were the waters in the fountains of the White House first dyed green in honor of Saint Patrick's Day?", "answer": "Barack Obama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6007810cbd51d85e222ab647", "question": "What art movement literally means the style of \"the wild beasts\"?", "answer": "Fauvism\u00a0(The movement emphasized vivid expressionism and unnatural use of color over representational or realistic values.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe76c3eeec85e375820b2ce", "question": "In which U.S. city was cream cheese invented?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a17", "question": "Which composer of the \"Rite of Spring\" was still alive to see his music used in Disney's \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Igor Stravinsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b780", "question": "What city's Summer Olympics had the beaver Amik as their mascot?", "answer": "Montreal's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba26", "question": "In the world of business, what does the abbreviation NYSE stand for?", "answer": "New York Stock Exchange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b2f901dd7bf43be5e7a5", "question": "What team retired Michael Jordan\u2019s jersey despite him never playing for them?", "answer": "Miami Heat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca0", "question": "When do \"blue laws\" prohibit certain activities?", "answer": "On Sundays", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60062a09c9d816e292245c12", "question": "Which German painter was best known for his depictions of naval warfare in World War I?", "answer": "Claus Bergen (1885-1964) developed a specialty of painting naval subjects, as well as fishing scenes and coastal views.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339012", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Bridge Over the River Kwai\"?", "answer": "Pierre Boulle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32e", "question": "Most people breathe through one nostril at a time - True or False?", "answer": "True, over 85% of people breather through only one nostril at a time", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c3", "question": "What composer founded the \"Barking Pumpkin\" record label?", "answer": "Frank Zappa", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe938a76bd93ce3a4e5f687", "question": "What is the standard unit of kinetic energy?", "answer": "Joule", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015e2a7fe83fe1f2a824ba1", "question": "What Japanese action created tension with the United States?", "answer": "Japan's seizure of territory in China", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5bfdffe3b668d7dfe168b5bd", "question": "Chablis wine comes from which French wine region?", "answer": "Burgundy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac9b", "question": "Who was prime minister of the United Kingdom from 1997 to 2007?", "answer": "Tony Blair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb48", "question": "In what year was Ben & Jerry's founded?", "answer": "1978", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a07c", "question": "What actor played the leading role in \"The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly\"?", "answer": "Clint Eastwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff516f0ff04d658268c92f7", "question": "Egyptian workers were often paid with a ration of what?", "answer": "Beer (It was so beloved in Ancient Egypt that it was an accepted form of currency.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeec", "question": "In which year did the Japanese attack Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "1941", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a2", "question": "What is the official language of Egypt?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a728c336bcd28c119383282", "question": "What is the name of Christopher Lee's autobiography?", "answer": "Tall, Dark and Gruesome", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c146", "question": "How many dots are there on a die?", "answer": "21", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c8a50e90aac110e4167070", "question": "What is Homer Simpson\u2019s beer of choice?", "answer": "Duff", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338946", "question": "Which singer's 2000 autobiography \"Chasing Down the Dawn\" detailed her life growing up in Alaska?", "answer": "Jewel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396f4", "question": "Who\u2019s Fred Flintstone\u2019s best friend?", "answer": "Barney Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c82d", "question": "What kind of dental specialist performs root canals?", "answer": "An endodontist", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b6", "question": "What movie stars Marlon Brando as a boxer who stands up against a corrupt union?", "answer": "On the Waterfront", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e910021d7247dfc0fa0030c", "question": "The first U.S. state park was created in which state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59f9bbd8364247bf200fb8a9", "question": "What country borders Zambia to the north?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa04", "question": "The Gorbals is a district of which city?", "answer": "Glasgow", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db77020ab2c8f322317fea", "question": "Who played Norman Bates in the 1998 film \"Psycho\"?", "answer": "Vince Vaughn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe37a6d0ada16518afdc059", "question": "How many concentration camps did Nazi Germany operate in Occupied Poland?", "answer": "457", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e8", "question": "What country singer recorded a popular album at Folsom Prison?", "answer": "Johnny Cash", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aacc", "question": "What city is the capital of the US state of Kansas?", "answer": "Topeka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be7b", "question": "What slang term for the stomach is the highest-scoring ailment in the game \"Operation\"?", "answer": "The Breadbasket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf1", "question": "In what year was famous designer Giorgio Armani born?", "answer": "1934", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eaa", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"High Society\"?", "answer": "Grace Kelly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfdde9616e6c6d4eba4f9", "question": "What is the plural of the word \"crisis\"?", "answer": "Crises", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acb6", "question": "Which Greek island was the center of the Minoan civilization?", "answer": "Crete", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c859", "question": "What are the only two consecutive prime numbers?", "answer": "2 and 3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a848", "question": "What Canadian Province is located between Saskatchewan and Ontario?", "answer": "Manitoba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae5", "question": "Who played Ike Turner in the 1993 Tina Turner biopic \"What's Love Got To Do With It?\"", "answer": "Laurence Fishburne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb4", "question": "What violinist performed the title character's solos in the film \"Fiddler on the Roof\"?", "answer": "Isaac Stern", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b09", "question": "In Greek mythology, what did Medusa have on her head instead of hair?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990f386fa5fdd6dd25324db", "question": "What company developed and manufactured the Pentium microprocessor?", "answer": "Intel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91f", "question": "Which fish, previously thought to be extinct was rediscovered In 1939?", "answer": "The Coelacanth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5db03f44aa1c9af2684d79a6", "question": "Who was the mother of the Minotaur?", "answer": "Pasipha\u00eb", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edc", "question": "What position was first held by Caesar Augustus?", "answer": "Emperor of Rome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5aab2f0058d116dab4aecb45", "question": "What is the scientific method of dating tree rings called?", "answer": "Dendrochronology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59bb2911c9bff04efae6d754", "question": "In what 1967 film did Gene Hackman earn his first Oscar nomination?", "answer": "Bonnie and Clyde", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd03", "question": "It is sometimes considered a fashion faux pas to wear white after what holiday?", "answer": "Labor Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6df", "question": "What US territory includes the islands of Saint Croix, Saint John and Saint Thomas?", "answer": "US Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f85", "question": "In the nursery rhyme what is Friday's child?", "answer": "Loving and Giving", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b474", "question": "What year did Andre and Edouard Michelin first publish the \"Michelin Guide\"?", "answer": "1900", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59636e1d967692ea851899b1", "question": "\"Back to Us\" is the name of what band's 10th studio album?", "answer": "Rascal Flatts'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a87c", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Yonge Street\"?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c38", "question": "What band performed the theme song from the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ed3a06d333868d34d76b", "question": "The first TV commercial for a toy aired in 1952 featuring what toy?", "answer": "Mr. Potato Head", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1c", "question": "Where in the UK would you go to celebrate \"Uphelia'' shortly after Christmas?", "answer": "Shetland Isles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ded", "question": "What TV show's theme song was called \"The Fishin' Hole\"?", "answer": "The Andy Griffith Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b869", "question": "What kind of beans are dropped into a Sambuca?", "answer": "Coffee beans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a931", "question": "What is the only nation that shares a land border with Haiti?", "answer": "The Dominican Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc4", "question": "By including cannon fire in his play, Henry VIII, Shakespeare caused the 1613 fire that destroyed what building?", "answer": "The Globe Theatre", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6003951257a0e35c43f83891", "question": "Any color plus white is called what?", "answer": "A tint", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6a0", "question": "What\u2019s the name of the science of growing plants in liquid nutrients instead of soil?", "answer": "Hydroponics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf2", "question": "Who created the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "Tomohiro Nishikado", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cefc2c3948005ec986edceb", "question": "What season did The Simpsons enter in 2018?", "answer": "30", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b32342bbf195a31e15d73a3", "question": "What are a Galliard, Sarabande, and Courante?", "answer": "Dance types", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ad", "question": "Brisbane is the state capital of which Australian state?", "answer": "Queensland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef5bef6ce05a3942286e1b", "question": "Who directed the film \"Hacksaw Ridge\"?", "answer": "Mel Gibson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7a1cff048f679a45abe7", "question": "What is the scientific term for peeling skin?", "answer": "Desquamation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c3094f032c0db195b489", "question": "Who was the first European to discover New Zealand?", "answer": "Abel Janszoon Tasman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab27", "question": "Antananarivo is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b373", "question": "What country's explorers discovered the site of Pensacola, Florida?", "answer": "Spain's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c660", "question": "What is the purpose of \"seeding\" a cloud?", "answer": "To create rain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5937ee0308d98002fdd633cf", "question": "What is a strong aversion to beards known as?", "answer": "Pogonophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015deadfe83fe1f2a824b70", "question": "What was a claw-like weapon from India designed to fit over the knuckles?", "answer": "Bagh naka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c88e87222f44c2d77a29c47", "question": "Where is the deepest land gorge in the US?", "answer": "Along the border of eastern Oregon, eastern Washington and western Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ff3", "question": "What movie star founded the Hole in the Wall summer camps for ill children?", "answer": "Paul Newman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae11", "question": "Who was Henry VIII's first wife?", "answer": "Catherine of Aragon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17e", "question": "Jenny and Linn Berggren are singers with which 1990's group?", "answer": "Ace of Base", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede5006ce05a3942286de4", "question": "What were George Harrison's names in the Traveling Wilburys?", "answer": "Nelson and Spike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c693", "question": "What do astronomers call an interstellar cloud of dust dust, hydrogen, helium and other ionized gases?", "answer": "Nebula", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e3cd06d333868d34d72f", "question": "Who invented the first steam locomotive?", "answer": "George Stephenson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a0f520565ad31a57c79e", "question": "Who was the first woman to appear on American currency?", "answer": "Pocahontas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339543", "question": "Who hosted \"The Hollywood Squares\" between 1986 and 1989?", "answer": "John Davidson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb06", "question": "Since 1949, what magazine has handed out the most prestigious \"Car of the Year\" Award?", "answer": "Motor Trend", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f7d3fe83fe1f2a824c27", "question": "A young women in the 1920's that behaved and dressed boldly was referred to as what?", "answer": "A flapper", "category": "history"}, {"id": "594d06b51a1c922dd1ac64af", "question": "What's the official state sport of Alaska?", "answer": "Dog mushing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a206", "question": "What comedy team's films included \"Hollywood or Bust\" and \"Living It Up\"?", "answer": "Dean Martin and Jerry Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff214fe31a458464a93c45b", "question": "Who came up with \"The Allegory of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d474caf8e329de4f8778a0", "question": "The Balfour Declaration was published in what year?", "answer": "1917", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b14a", "question": "In 1998, John Glenn returned to space aboard which space shuttle?", "answer": "Discovery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febd4ca7e83c707845b2160", "question": "In the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\", which character had his hands replaced by the director, Frank Darabont, as insert shot?", "answer": "Andy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ac7301dd7bf43be5e76b", "question": "The \"Malleus Maleficarum\" was a 15th-century guide to dealing with what?", "answer": "Witches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a73a", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Sunflower State\"?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f7298a9e54d890926f6ec", "question": "In which U.S. city can you stroll down 6 1/2 Avenue?", "answer": "New York City -- Made official in 2012, the street is situated between 6th Avenue and 7th Avenue.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339738", "question": "What is the number of the house \"The Simpsons\" live in at Evergreen Terrace, Springfield?", "answer": "742", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b041", "question": "In 1626, what island was purchased by Peter Minuit from the natives for goods valued at $24?", "answer": "Manhattan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed3", "question": "What game did Charles Darrow based upon the \"The Landlord's Game\"?", "answer": "Monopoly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe4ddaa06d333868d34d706", "question": "During World War II, where was \"Hacksaw Ridge\" located?", "answer": "Okinawa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e2d506d333868d34d72a", "question": "What is the United States Bill of Rights?", "answer": "The first ten amendments to the U.S. Constitution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baba", "question": "What team did the Green Bay Packers defeat in Super Bowl II?", "answer": "Oakland Raiders", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6003952d57a0e35c43f83893", "question": "Any color plus grey is called what?", "answer": "A tone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133975f", "question": "What two murderesses does Billy Flynn represent in Chicago?", "answer": "Velma Kelly and Roxie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fd16fe83fe1f2a824c4a", "question": "In what country is the skull of St. Valentine of Rome said to be kept?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae22", "question": "What are the four permanent, non-US members of the United Nations Security Council?", "answer": "China, France, Russia, United Kingdom", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10d", "question": "In ancient Greece, what color hair was associated with prostitution?", "answer": "Blonde", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b73", "question": "Who wrote the play \"Death of a Salesman\"?", "answer": "Arthur Miller", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f03bff048f679a45aa9a", "question": "Podophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Feet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eae7df83302ff91e46489", "question": "What is a group of deer called?", "answer": "A Herd", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc75", "question": "What year were Reese's Peanut Butter Cups first introduced to the US market?", "answer": "1928", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f1687cf7c52aae91cc07c8", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015fcd3fe83fe1f2a824c45", "question": "Which toy\u2019s original patented name was the \"whirligig\"?", "answer": "Yo-yo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fd7", "question": "Who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time'' In 1988?\u00a0", "answer": "Stephen Hawking\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff0b0cae662d71a53650fcc", "question": "What is the name of the magical map of Hogwarts School?", "answer": "Marauder's Map", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecd094ec223966ae8f88b9", "question": "In the 1998 movie \"The Man in the Iron Mask\", which character dies defending Philippe?", "answer": "D'Artagnan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a0", "question": "How many tusks sprout from the snout of an adult male warthog?", "answer": "4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a70", "question": "Who has a heart \"two sizes too small\"?", "answer": "The Grinch", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd69f486c0f9723ab15cb29", "question": "Who was the first woman to win the Pulitzer Prize?", "answer": "Edith Wharton", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2a", "question": "In what Australian state would you find Whyalla?", "answer": "South Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b68a", "question": "What company introduced the first automatic washing machine at the Louisiana State Fair in 1937?", "answer": "Bendix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e2", "question": "What 1999 movie features the line \"What kind of dining set defines me as a person\"?", "answer": "Fight Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595641ae803c1f1ebcc4a02a", "question": "The ball on top of a flag pole is called a what?", "answer": "Truck", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c669", "question": "Who developed the light bulb while working in his Menlo Park laboratory?", "answer": "Thomas Edison", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe5225e1bf59ab7d2e380e7", "question": "What is the soft, triangular, fleshy part of the inside of a horse's hoof called?", "answer": "Frog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a332", "question": "What was the name of Ross' pet monkey on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Marcell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339637", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Esmeralda?", "answer": "Quasimodo's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ab", "question": "What year was Tabasco sauce first produced?", "answer": "1868", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff7c1d22b316f4693fb679e", "question": "What is eaten traditionally in the UK the day before Ash Wednesday?", "answer": "Pancakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2a8", "question": "What year did Humphrey Bogart die?", "answer": "1957", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a642", "question": "What city is known as the \"Capital of the Silicon Valley\"?", "answer": "San Jose", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe733f0eec85e375820b229", "question": "What naval battle between Mark Antony and Octavian is often said to mark the beginning of the Roman Empire?", "answer": "Battle of Actium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2590931a458464a93c469", "question": "The most viewed photo in the world was featured where?", "answer": "Microsoft Windows XP background, \"Bliss\" (a photograph by Charles O\u2019Rear)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133989f", "question": "What movie is set in the year 2154 on the moon of Pandora?", "answer": "Avatar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bdc", "question": "Lenny Kravtiz is the son of what popular sitcom actress?", "answer": "Roxie Roker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e42", "question": "What slave name does Kunta Kinte's owner force him to adopt in Alex Haley's \"Roots\"?", "answer": "Toby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c3e99a0ebfabb9c85d8a974", "question": "Whose first wife was actress Jane Wyman?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfc779dc5ec6cd98a831d", "question": "What Brazilian artist was known for his fireballs?", "answer": "In the 1960s, H\u00e9lio Oiticica produced a series of small box-shaped interactive sculptures called B\u00f3lides (fireballs).", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133898c", "question": "What snack gave Mickey Mouse his first spoken words?", "answer": "Hot dogs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a133", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl's brother?", "answer": "Castor Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe0e306fcbed638185eaa1f", "question": "Where is the United Nations (UN) Headquarters located?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b20c", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5c1", "question": "What does Ambidextrous mean?", "answer": "Equally skilled with both hands", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf8", "question": "Who wrote \"Uncle Tom's Cabin\"?", "answer": "Harriet Beecher Stowe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015f092fe83fe1f2a824c11", "question": "According to legend which was the favorite flower of Venus, the Roman goddess of love?", "answer": "Red roses", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acad", "question": "What was Al Capone's nickname?", "answer": "Scarface", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f90", "question": "Which character is the narrator of Melville's \"Moby Dick\"?", "answer": "Ishmael", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60121c2b63c99d48cd169b12", "question": "Norman Rockwell painted 323 covers for which magazine?", "answer": "\"Saturday Evening Post\" -- The magazine featured Rockwell\u2019s work from 1916 to 1963.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b509", "question": "What two months are named for men?", "answer": "July and August", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba80", "question": "What was the original name of \"TV Guide\"?", "answer": "TV Digest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa85f6ce05a3942286ecf", "question": "In the film \"Aliens\", what is Newt's birth name?", "answer": "Rebecca", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96dda23c87fd04dd15e30", "question": "Who was the first U.S. Vice President to resign?", "answer": "John C. Calhoun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58d119d74fea7fe947a22291", "question": "Who was known as the \"Clown Prince\" of basketball?", "answer": "Meadowlark Lemon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25ee9e6682715b82711cce", "question": "Which European republic was the first to reach Australia in 1606?", "answer": "The Dutch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133937c", "question": "What actor plays the role of the Bible salesman in the movie \"O Brother, Where Art Thou\"?", "answer": "John Goodman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b36df71c3f17ccc40c8e07", "question": "Who wrote and directed the 1999 film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "M. Night Shyamalan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f53", "question": "Which US actor is the first to star in 8 consecutive number one hit movies?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8c", "question": "Which celebrity launched a perfume range entitled \"M\" in 2007?", "answer": "Mariah Carey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c8", "question": "Which US state has the least rainfall?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fde", "question": "What 1959 Dave Brubeck Quartet piece borrows its name from its unusual time signature?", "answer": "Take Five", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea37c0ff048f679a45ab1d", "question": "What is the rarest blood type?", "answer": "AB negative", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c579", "question": "What organ is physically altered by a lobotomy?", "answer": "Brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ec7220857c9fcac0ce71975", "question": "Each year, about how many Mint Juleps are served over Kentucky Oaks and Kentucky Derby weekend?", "answer": "120,000", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000ed7f9a72b906b34e3cec", "question": "Who discovered the mathematical system of logarithms?", "answer": "John Napier", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad19", "question": "What bird did Benjamin Franklin favor for America's national emblem?", "answer": "The turkey", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f51", "question": "\"Girls with a Pearl Earring\" is one of only thirty-five extant works of what Dutch painter?", "answer": "Jan Vermeer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b0", "question": "What is the name of the coffee shop the \"Friends\" gang frequents?", "answer": "Central Perk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baad", "question": "Taekwondo was developed in what country?", "answer": "Korea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008df8cf842fa4c4ba96ae", "question": "In the world of wine, what does \"Chambre\" mean?", "answer": "Serve at room temperature", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b3711b1c3f17ccc40c8e1c", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b174691bb2d29f81593b708", "question": "What were the name of the two space shuttles in the 1998 film \"Armageddon\"?", "answer": "Freedom and Independence", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a018", "question": "What actor was the narrator in the 2000 movie \"How the Grinch Stole Christmas\"?", "answer": "Anthony Hopkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396e4", "question": "What kind of a car travels through time in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "DeLorean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec0", "question": "On April 11, 1990, California Angel Mike Witt combined with which starter to pitch a no-hit victory?", "answer": "Mark Langston", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ab", "question": "Which middle layer of a tooth contains the root canals?", "answer": "The dentin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fdabd760b8cce1e6fda7063", "question": "What meat is the primary ingredient in Booyah, a thick stew?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29e", "question": "Who was the male lead in the 1955 film \"To Catch a Thief\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4a", "question": "What Latin phrase actually comes from a poem, attributed to Virgil, about a salad recipe?", "answer": "E Pluribus Unum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3c", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Gone with the Wind\"?", "answer": "Margaret Mitchell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc28d6de0eb824d4052e6", "question": "What is the nickname for the island of Trinidad?", "answer": "Land of the Hummingbird", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339172", "question": "Mark Hamill was a voice actor for which popular early 90's superhero cartoon?", "answer": "Batman: The Animated Series", "category": "entertainment"}]